JAMES RHODES

Date of Birth 08/10/1980

Address Dongzhimen, Beijing
Mobile +86 152 01422158
Email vincerhodes@gmail.com

Career Profile

An IT Operations manager accomplished in all phases of the design, development, testing & implementation of operational processes and systems. ITIL certified with in-depth knowledge of OSS systems, a drive for efficiency and 8 years' experience in the telecommunications industry delivering successful Governance & Continuous Improvement initiatives in agile, high pressure environments

Over 10 years' experience in the design, development, delivery and testing of software both in-house and through external suppliers. Strategic input into data migration projects and cultural change programmes as part of the THUS and Cable & Wireless acquisitions.

Has a firm grasp on the fundamentals of modern IT industry with over 3 years' experience delivering ITIL aligned continuous improvement projects for the Director of Service, engaging with all areas of operations, Service Management and external customers. Highly experienced in database development, SQL and programming with an extensive knowledge of SharePoint, Business Intelligence (BOXI) and other reporting solutions

Skills, Competencies and Qualifications

Full Vodafone management training (Myers Briggs, personality profiling, coaching etc.)

Experienced in production of IT demand requests, business cases and budgets

Mathematical, statistical analysis, financial analysis, forecasting and reporting skills

Process analysis and process improvement

Development and delivery of OSS systems in-house and through external suppliers

Production of requirements capture, UAT & BRT scripts, development and delivery of training materials

ITIL V3 Certified and experienced in delivering ITIL aligned projects

Six Sigma Continuous Improvement green belt training

Significant experience in integration and transformation programmes

Project Management & direct management experience

Skilled in developing Databases and systems using Access and Excel, very advanced with Visual Basic for Applications

Excellent IT literacy across the board, highly skilled in automation with IT

Full, clean UK driving licence and Chinese driving licence

Excellent communication skills, presentation skills and grammatical competency

Technologies

VBA, HTML, CSS, SQL, C++ and Java Microsoft Access Developer and Administrator

OSS systems (Remedy, Cramer, Clarify etc.)

Business Objects 11 (BOXI)

MPLS, IpVPN QOS, Hosting, Cloud, FMC, WAN, LAN Business Warehouse

SharePoint 2010 Developer and Administrator Crystal Reporting

Career History

Oct 2017 - Present

Independent Salesforce Consultant (part time)

• End to end delivery of custom Salesforce implementations, involved in negotiation, design, development, testing and delivery of the end solution.

Nov 2015 – Present

The British Embassy Beijing Visa Section – Software Developer (part time since Nov 2017)

- Sole accountability for designing, developing, testing and delivering software solutions to support 200+ staff in the British Embassy visa section.
- Highlights include the inception of Issue Notes and Streaming software which both incorporate the use of the HTML Document Object Model to automate parts of the roles of 200 staff. This has reduced human error, enable more complex and accurate triage, and improved the throughput of the entire operation.
- Delivered over 100 small, medium and large IT projects over a 2-year timeframe.
- Awarded employee of the year 2017 and in May 2018 awarded a global innovation award for leading an IT training programme that delivered essential training to almost all of the staff in Beijing and is in the process of being rolled out worldwide with support from the Head of Immigration

Jun 2014 - Nov 2015

Vodafone UK, Technology Enterprise Services – Senior Manager, Demand Forecasting

- Accountable for establishing and running a forecasting team within Vodafone UK, providing resource demand forecasting for over 1900 people.
- Accountability for inputs into budget planning cycles and translation of sales & product budget plans into impact on TES
- Line management responsibilities for a team of performance analysts and systems specialists
- Accountability for forecasting recommendations and analysis to the Senior management team, presenting the findings at monthly operational reviews and ensuring actions followed through by the functional teams
- Enabling business decisions on major bids and the impact those bids will have on TES
- Working closely with IT to develop new forecasting capabilities, providing input into projects and programmes aimed at maturing forecasting across the wider business
- End-to-end accountability for requirements capture, demand requests and Business Cases for new systems/software
- Development of UAT and BRT scripts, oversight of testing, production and delivery of training packages
- Development of new tools and capabilities in SharePoint, MS Access, MS Excel and MS InfoPath

Feb 2011 - Jun 2014

Vodafone Global Enterprise, (Formerly Cable & Wireless Worldwide) – Continuous Improvement Manager

- Accountable for ensuring the department hits annual Margin Maximisation targets with targets hit for FY 12/13 and over-delivering against FY 13/14 target (targets of £4M 12/13 & £3M 13/14)
- Responsibility for the management and end-to-end delivery of ITIL aligned Governance & Continuous Improvement projects
- Business wide engagement with internal and external IT stakeholders
- Accountable for all stages of design, testing, training and implementation of global IT projects
- Project management of business change initiatives
- Accountability for SharePoint, Business Intelligence, complex Microsoft Access and other reporting solutions
- Development and delivery of training packages with up to 200 colleagues in attendance
- Project and MI reporting up to board level

Previous Career History

Nov 2017 - Present Independent Squash Coach

 Playing squash to a high level I delivery squash coaching for children mainly from Keystone in Beijing, aside from squash skills the coaching is very much focussed on personal life skills such as leadership, motivation, responsibility and other personality attributes in order to develop interpersonal skills

Oct 2008 – Feb 2011	Cable & Wireless Worldwide (Formerly THUS) – HSBC Service Manager
Apr 2008 – Oct 2008	THUS plc. – HSBC Junior Service Manager
Aug 2006 – Apr 2008	THUS plc. – HSBC Programme Co-ordinator
Sep 2005 – Jul 2006	Siemens Business Services – Service Delivery Co-ordinator
Sep 2003 – Jul 2006	The University of Sheffield – Personal Tutor
Jun 2003 - Sep 2003	Questions Answered, York – Data administrator
Apr 2002 – Jun 2003	Questions Answered, York – Telephone research and data inputting
Aug 1999 – Aug 2001	Railpart (UK) Limited – The Year In Industry, Doncaster
Jun 1997 – Sep 1997	Dave Cook Racing Services (DCRS), York

Education		
2000 – 2004	University of Sheffield MEng/Aero – Aerospace Engineering Masters Degree, 2-1	
1999 – 2000	Pershore Business College, Worcester NEBS Business Management Qualification, PASS	
1997 – 1999	Adams' Grammar School, Shropshire A-Levels; Mathematics A; Physics B; Further Maths D	

Personal Profile

I'm a highly motivated and sociable both in and out of work. Through the Vodafone charity scheme I've driven out of hours charitable fundraising activities for Cancer Research with the team I manage. I play Squash to a high standard and Captain a team in the Sheffield league whilst also playing in Yorkshire league.

In Beijing I cycle around 1000km a month from April to October and regularly take part in local Sportives. In my free time I'm developing an App for iPhone and Android.